LUCAS GANSBERG

Father, husband, tinkerer, fullstack software engineer



(541)-591-8020

✓ lucas.gansberg@gmail.com



in www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-gansberg

SKILLS

Technologies

- React
- Vue
- NodeJS
- Terraform
- Docker
- GH Actions
- · Figma/Sketch
- AWS
 - SQS
 - SNS
 - DvnamoDB
 - Lambda
 - OpenSearch
 - CloudFront

Languages & Markup

- Javascript/TypeScript
- Golang
- C# .NET
- C++
- HTML/CSS
- GraphQL

Architecture

- REST
- Microservices

STRENGTHS

Self-Motivated Problem-Solving **Technical Management**

EDUCATION

B.S. Software Engineering Oregon Institute of Technology

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 12 years of industry experience. For the past two years I've managed a team of four highly skilled engineers, working on a variety of projects. I'm currently interested in leading another skilled group of engineers or working by their side.

EXPERIENCE



Software Engineering Manager

May 2021 - Present

- Managed a team of 4 developers responsible for 5 internal platforms, SDKs, libraries, and customer support.
- Lead the cross-functional engagement to re-architect our internal IdP provisioning platform.
- Collaborated daily with designers, developers, cross-functional teams, product, and program.
- · Developed engineering roadmaps and managed tasks to deliver features to our product catalog.



Senior Software Engineer III

May 2019 - March 2021

- Built an internal AWS type console, to provide a one stop shop for technical products, and documentation.
- Delivered a Digital Asset Management platform UI
- Stood up an internal Data enrichment metric service
- IdP provisioning and documentation services.
- · Worked on multiple greenfield products.



Senior Software Engineer II

March 2016 - May 2019

- Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) Scheduler leveraging gRPC for comms. access by either API or a UI.
- UI designed to manage a server rack's physical resources based on the workloads requirements for compute, storage, and memory requirements.



Software Engineer

July 2011 - March 2016

Software engineer focused on test automation, validating wireless standards/ protocols, wireless certification, and automation tools team.

- Worked on internal testing IDE and reporting tools.
- Wrapped native Intel wireless libraries using C# .NET for automated testing.
- Customer engagements to help leverage wireless features, along with OS integration: Microsoft, HP, Panasonic, and ActionTec.